在本次讲座中，
In this lecture,
我们将继续学习如何标记文本。
we will continue learning how to markup text.
所以我们会继续使用一些标题，
So we will keep using some headings,
一些段落，
some paragraphs,
我们还将学习如何使文本变为粗体和斜体。
and we will also learn how to make text bold and italic.
让我们从标题开始。
And let's actually start with headings.
所以通常标题的目标
So usually the goal of headings
是分解大块文本
is to break up big blocks of text
进入更多逻辑部分，
into more logical sections,
并基本上为每个部分添加标题。
and to basically add a title to each of the sections.
现在您已经了解了 h1 标题，
Now you already learned about the h1 heading,
但实际上有六个不同的标题。
but there are actually six different headings.
所以有标题的层次结构
So there's a hierarchy of headings
这样我们就可以在文本中建立层次结构。
so that we can establish a hierarchy in our text.
所以我们可以从h1一路走到h6。
So we can go all the way from h1 to h6.
所以让我们在这里抓住这段文字
So let's grab this text here
并创建所有这六个不同的标题，
and create all of these six different headings,
只是为了让您可以看到它们在视觉上的不同
just so you can see how they look different visually
在浏览器中。
in the browser.
所以 h1 我们可以称之为“主标题”，
So the h1 we can call the "Primary heading",
然后次要标题是h2。
and then the secondary heading is the h2.
我在这里粘贴完全相同的文本
And I'm pasting the exact same text here
所以我们可以看到它们之间的视觉差异。
so we can see the visual difference between them.
所以我们有 h1, h2,
So we have h1, h2,
然后是第三标题
and then for the tertiary heading
我们使用 h3。
we use h3.
在那里粘贴相同的文本。
Pasting the same text there.
现在我们只需要重复所有这些
And now we just have to repeat all of this
一直到h6。
all the way down to h6.
好的，
All right,
当你输入这个时，
and as you're typing this,
这些角色，
these characters,
所以这段代码，
so this code,
所有这一切都会开始进入你的大脑
all of this will start getting into your brain
您将开始练习编写 HTML。
and you will start getting practice writing HTML.
所以h6，
So h6,
然后让我们保存一下
and then let's give it a save
然后重新加载浏览器。
and then reloading the browser.
所以你可以很好地看到
And so you can see very nicely
这基本上创造了一个视觉层次
that this really created a visual hierarchy basically
这六个标题之间。
between these six headings.
所以第一个是迄今为止最大的一个，
So the first one is the biggest one by far,
然后是最后一个，
and then this last one,
这是h6
which is the h6
有点小。
is kind of small.
然后在两者之间，我们有所有这些不同的变化。
And then in between we have all these different variations.
现在好了。
Now okay.
所以现在我们知道了这些不同的标题是如何工作的，
So now we know how these different headings work,
但现在让我们来看看
but now let's take a look
实际上在我们的演示页面
at our demo page actually
只是为了看看我们真正需要哪种标题。
just to see which kind of headings we actually need.
所以我们基本上有了这个块的名称，
So we have basically the name of this block,
所以代码杂志，
so the code magazine,
这是最大的标题。
and this is the biggest heading.
然后在下面我们有文章的名称，
Then below that we have the name of the article,
所以这个块帖子，
so of this block post,
而且这个有点小，
and this one is a little bit smaller,
所以它不再是主要标题，
so it's not a primary heading anymore,
但它是次要标题。
but it is a secondary heading.
然后在这个文本里面，
Then inside of this text here,
并记得我是如何说那个标题的
and remembered how I said that heading
基本上是将文本分成逻辑部分，对吗？
is basically to break up texts into logical sections, right?
所以在这段文字之间
And so here in between this text
我们还有另一个部分。
we have another section.
所以在这里面，
And so here inside this,
比方说阻止帖子，
let's say block post,
我们还有另一个标题。
and we have another heading.
所以这应该是一个h3。
And so this should probably be an h3.
好的。
All right.
所以现在让我们为这种结构创建一个标记。
And so let's now create a markup for this kind of structure.
所以我们这里有我们实际需要的所有这些文本。
So we have all these texts that we need actually here.
所以我们只需要在这里复制粘贴这段代码，
So we just need to copy paste this code here,
或者本文。
or this text.
好的。
All right.
所以我现在把这个留在这里以供参考。
So I'm leaving this here for now for reference.
所以，
And so,
请记住，我们将从主要标题开始。
remember we are going to start with the primary heading.
所以我把它贴在这里
So I'll just paste this here
然后关闭h1。
and then close the h1.
现在好了。
Now okay.
然后让我们创建我们的辅助标题。
Then let's create our secondary heading.
我会再次抓住
And again I will grab
来自这里的文本。
the texts from here.
所以那是...
And so that's...
嗯，这实际上是我们之前已经拥有的。
Well that's actually the one that we already had before.
所以这个和这个完全一样，
So this one is exactly the same as this one,
但这并不重要。
but that doesn't really matter.
没问题。
It's no problem.
然后让我们得到我们的 h3
And then let's get our h3
这就是 HTML。
which is what is HTML.
我们就这么写吧。
Let's just write that.
然后让我们看看这是什么样子
And then let's check out what this looks like
现在我们开始。
and here we go.
好的。
Nice.
所以这是一种结构
So this is kind of the structure
我们现在的文字，
of our text right now,
现在我们只需要把它填满
and now we just need to fill it up
与中间的段落。
with the paragraphs in between.
所以基本上对于这些段落中的每一个
So basically for each of these paragraphs
我们在文本中
that we have in the text
我们可以简单地创建一个段落和一个代码。
we can simply create a paragraph and a code.
对？
Right?
而且我们之前已经使用了段落元素，
And we already used the paragraph element before,
所以这是一种通用元素
and so that's kind of a generic element
我们用来标记更大的文本块。
that we use to mark up bigger blocks of text.
所以记住那是“p”元素，
So remember that's the "p" element,
让我在这里抓取内容。
and let me just grab the content here.
所以我们在这里的第一个
So the first one that we have here
由劳拉·琼斯于 6 月 21 日星期一发布。
is posted by Laura Jones on Monday, June 21st.
让我复制一下。
Let me copy it.
哦，你现在看到了吗
Oh and do you see that now
该元素再次自动关闭。
this element was again closed automatically.
让我们在这里保存一下。
Let's give it a save here.
现在让我们在这里创建一些额外的段落。
And now let's create some additional paragraphs here.
所以p元素，
So the p element,
让我在这里立即关闭它，
and let me actually close it immediately here,
然后让我们抓取我们的文本。
and then let's grab our text.
所以这里就是这个。
So it's this one here.
所以复制
So copy
并粘贴。
and paste.
所以现在我们开始
And so by now we are starting
同时建立一个真正的我们的项目
to build a really our project at the same time
作为学习这些元素。
as learning about these elements.
所以这里也有这个，
So this one here as well,
所以我再次复制它
so I'm copying it again
然后将其粘贴到 p 元素中。
and then pasting it inside of the p element.
所以让我们保存一下
So let's give it a save
并重新加载
and reload it again
这看起来已经不错了。
and that's looking nice already.
伟大的。
Great.
让我们来看看，
Let's take a look,
现在让我们再抓两个，
and now let's just grab two more,
所以这两个段落在这里。
so these two paragraphs here.
所以在我们在这里的h3之后，
So after the h3 that we have down here,
所以“p”并立即关闭它。
so "p" and closing it immediately as well.
所以只需双击选择所有它，
So just double clicking to selecting all of it,
只是一个不错的技术。
just a nice technique.
然后让我们添加最后一个。
And then let's just add the final one.
同时你会看到
And you'll see that in the meantime
它在这里格式化为代码
it formatted to code here
那是因为自动保存
and that's because of the auto save
和自动格式。
and the auto format.
好的，
Okay,
现在我实际上手动保存了它。
now I saved it manually actually.
我们去这里
Let's go here
又是我们的内容。
and there is our content again.
现在稍微清理一下
Now to clean this up a little bit
现在让我们真正摆脱
let's now actually get rid
所有这六个标题在这里。
of all of these six headings here.
所以现在你已经知道它们是如何工作的
So now you already know how they work
并且它们存在。
and that they exist.
实际上不是摆脱它们，
And actually instead of getting rid of them,
我们可以在 HTML 中使用一种叫做“评论”的东西。
we can use something called "Comments" in HTML.
所以 HTML 中的注释
So a comment in HTML
是一种编写代码的方式
is a way of writing some code
这将在浏览器中不可见。
that will not be visible in the browser.
这非常有用
And this is very useful
因为它允许我们写关于我们的代码的注释，
because it allows us to write comments about our code,
或者也简单地隐藏一些代码
or also to simply hide some code
我们不想在浏览器上呈现。
that we do not want to be rendered on the browser.
现在写评论
Now to write a comment
这有点奇怪的语法。
it's a little bit of a weird syntax.
所以我们再次写小于符号，
So again we write the less than symbol,
然后是感叹号，
then an exclamation mark,
然后破折号，
then dash dash,
然后关闭评论VS代码
and then to close the comment VS code
已经自动创建，
already automatically created,
这个破折号关闭部分。
this dash dash closing part.
所以这会打开一个新评论
So this opens a new comment
这将关闭相同的评论。
and this closes that same comment.
现在让我们在这里删除这部分
Now let's remove this part here
现在你会看到一切都变灰了。
and now you'll see that everything turned gray.
所以现在所有这些都是评论，
So all of this is a comment now,
但我们实际上想要评论
but we actually want the comment
到此结束。
to end right here.
所以“破折号”并关闭，
So "dash dash" and close,
现在这里只有这部分是灰色的，
and now only this part here is gray,
这意味着这现在是评论
which means that this is now the comment
现在它不会被渲染。
and it will now not be rendered.
所以让我们检查一下。
So let's check that out.
如果我重新加载，
And if I reload,
现在它从页面上消失了。
now it is gone from the page.
好的。
Nice.
但是我们仍然可以将其保留在代码中
But we can still keep it here in the code
只是为了让你知道 h1、2、3、4、5 和 6 也存在。
just so you know that h1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and six also exist.
现在只是我之前没有提到的一件事
Now just one thing that I didn't mention earlier
关于标题
about the headings
是每一页
is that each and every page
应该只有一个 h1 一个标题。
should only have one h1 one heading.
所以只有一个主标题。
So only one primary heading.
记住这一点非常重要。
That it's very important to keep in mind.
这并不是强制性的
This is not really mandatory
所以它不会违反任何 HTML 规则
so it doesn't violate any HTML rules
如果我们有多个 h1，
if we have multiple h1's,
但这是一个很好的做法
but it is a very good practice
总是只有其中一个。
to always just have one of them.
现在关于所有其他的，
Now about all the other ones,
我们当然可以拥有多个。
we can have of course multiple of them.
例如，
So for example,
我认为在我们的页面上我们实际上有
I think on our page we actually have
这些标题中的另一个在这里
another of these headings here
在我们的文本中间。
in the middle of our text.
所以在我们的例子中，
And so in our case,
这些是 h3 标题。
these are h3 headings.
所以你看，
So you see,
这是另一个。
here is another one.
所以当然我们也可以在这里添加
So of course we can also add that here
马上，
right away,
为什么不？
why not?
所以h3，
So h3,
"为什么要学习 HTML？",
"Why should you learn HTML?",
然后当然关闭它。
and then of course closing it.
好的。
Okay.
现在刚刚结束，
Now just to finish,
让我也快速告诉你
let me also quickly show you
我们如何创建粗体
how we can create bold
和斜体文字。
and a italic text.
所以在我们的演示站点
So here in our demo site
我们有这个作者的名字，
we have this name of the author,
这是粗体的“劳拉琼斯”。
which is "Laura Jones" in bold.
那么我们如何在 HTML 中做到这一点呢？
So how can we do that in HTML?
嗯，有一个特殊的元素，
Well there is a special element for that,
或者实际上是两个元素。
or actually two elements.
让我从一个更简单的开始，
And let me start with a simpler one,
简称为“b”。
which is simply called "b".
所以B代表“粗体”。
So B stands for "Bold".
所以我们想要大胆的部分，
And so the part that we want to be bold,
所以“劳拉琼斯”在这种情况下，
so "Laura Jones" in this case,
他们要做的一切
all they have to do
就是把它放在一个 b 元素里面。
is to put it inside of a b element.
所以我们可以写
So we can just write
b 像这样
b like this
在一开始的时候
in the beginning
然后在内容的最后
and then at the end of the content
我们只需添加结束标签。
we simply add our closing tag.
所以这是“/ b”，
So that's "/b",
关闭它，
close it,
现在一旦我们重新加载或拥有页面。
and now once we reload or own page.
所以看看这里的“劳拉琼斯”，
So take a look here at "Laura Jones",
如果我们重新加载
if we reload that
然后你看到它变成了粗体，
then you see that it turned bold,
很棒。
and great.
然而现在，
Now however,
使用 b 实际上不是一个好习惯。
the use of b is actually not a good practice.
所以 b 实际上是一个较旧的 HTML 元素
So b is actually an older HTML element
从 HTML 5 开始，
and starting in HTML five,
我们应该始终使用 strong 元素而不是“b”。
we should always use the strong element instead of "b".
这样做的原因
The reason for that
就是b没有任何所谓的语义，
is that b doesn't have any so-called semantic meaning,
本节稍后会详细介绍。
and more about that a little bit later in this section.
但本质上这意味着什么
But essentially what this means
是 b 只是一个元素，
is that b is simply an element,
但没有具体含义，
but without a specific meaning,
而另一方面，强元素意味着
while on the other hand the strong element means that
这确实是一个重要的元素
this is really an important element
我们想从页面中脱颖而出。
that we want to stand out from the page.
所以如果我们在开始标签上说“强”，
So if we say "Strong" on the opening tag,
然后当然也在结束标签中，
and then of course also in the closing tag,
那么它将在浏览器中看起来完全一样。
then it will look exactly the same in the browser.
所以让我们确认一下。
So let's confirm.
是的，它仍然很大胆，
Yeah it's still bold,
但现在它有了意义
but now it has a meaning
这是一个更重要的文本。
that it is a more important text.
这本质上就是语义 HTML 的概念。
And that is essentially the idea of semantic HTML.
然后再次，
And again,
我们将更多地讨论语义 HTML
we will talk more about semantic HTML
在本节结束时。
by the end of this section.
所以现在只知道不要使用“b”，
So for now just know that don't use "b",
但使用“Strong”使文本变为粗体。
but use "Strong" to make text bold.
现在让我们在这里也让一些文字斜体，
Now let's also make some text italic here,
让我们在这里选择这个词。
and let's choose this word here.
所以只是基本的。
So just fundamental.
就像“b”一样，
And just like with "b",
实际上有两种方法。
there are actually two ways of doing it.
年纪大的
The older one
是“i”元素。
is the "i" element.
所以包装我们想要的文本的任何部分
So wrapping whatever part of the text we want
在 i 元素内为斜体。
to be italic inside of the i element.
“i”只代表斜体，
"i" just stands for italic,
事实上，
and indeed,
你看现在它变了，
you see that now it changed,
但是再一次为了使它成为语义 HTML，
but one more time in order to make this a semantic HTML,
我们不应该再使用“i”元素，
we should no longer use the "i" element,
但是“em”元素，
but the "em" element,
代表“强调”。
which stands for "Emphasize".
所以我们要在这里强调这段文字
So we want to emphasize this text here
这就是我们将其设为斜体的原因。
and that is the reason why we make it italic.
所以这也是浏览器的原因
So that's also the reason why the browser
然后显示为斜体，
then shows it as italic,
对？
right?
所以如果我们重新加载它仍然是斜体，
So if we reload it is still italic,
但现在我们基本上给了它意义
but now we basically gave it the meaning
强调的文本。
of an emphasized text.
现在好了，太好了。
Now okay, great.
这是一个很大的进步。
This is great progress.
到目前为止，你做得很好。
You're doing really well up until this point.
现在只是为了结束这个讲座，
Now just to finish this lecture,
其实我已经想给你了
I actually already want to give you
你的第一个小编码挑战。
your very first small coding challenge.
所以我想让你做什么
So what I want you to do
基本上就是这个。
is basically this.
让我在这里给你看。
Let me show it to you here.
所以我想让你把这些词的第一个字母，
So I want you to make the first letter of these words,
所以“超文本标记语言”，
so "Hyper Text Markup Language",
我想让你把 H、T、M 和 L 加粗。
I want you to make the H, T, M, and L bold.
好的。
All right.
所以基本上这就是这里的文本。
So basically that is this text right here.
所以这个H，
So this H,
这个T，
this T,
这个M，
this M,
而这个 L，
and this L,
他们都应该是大胆的。
they should all be bold.
所以他们应该在这里以粗体显示
So they should be displayed here in bold
就像我在演示页面中一样。
just like I have it in the demo page.
所以你认为你能做到吗
So do you think that you can do that
并自己编写一些 HTML 代码
and write some HTML code on your own
第一次？
for the very first time?
好吧，我真的希望你尝试一下
Well I really hope that you try it
因为正如我之前所说，
because as I said before,
这些编码挑战
these coding challenges
对你来说真的很重要
are really really important for you
开始练习你的技能，
to start practicing your skills,
即使它只是像这样非常简单的事情。
even if it's just something really simple like this.
所以请继续
So please go ahead
并立即暂停视频
and pause the video right now
并将这四个字母中的每一个都加粗，
and make each of these four letters bold,
我马上就会和你一起回来
and I will be back here in a second with you
向您展示它是如何完成的。
to show you how it's done.
那么你做到了吗？
So did you manage to do this?
嗯，这就是它的工作原理。
Well this is how it works.
所以再一次，
So once again,
我们只需要包装零件
we just need to wrap the parts
我们希望被标记为粗体，
that we want to be marked as bold,
化为强元素。
into a strong element.
在这种情况下，
And in this case,
那只是“h”
that is just the "h"
所以这就是我们关闭的原因
and so that's why we're closing
这个强大的元素就在这里
this strong element right here
在单词的中间。
in the middle of the word.
然后在这里我们想要“T”等等，
Then here we want the "T" and so again,
我们写...
we write...
再说一次，
And so again,
这里有一个强大的元素。
a strong element here.
所以开始标签，
So the opening tag,
然后另一个就在这里。
and then the other one right here.
当然，其他两个字母也是如此。
And of course then the same for the other two letters.
现在好了。
Now okay.
所以希望我没有在那里犯任何错误。
So hopefully I didn't do any mistake there.
让我们重新加载
Let's reload
你去吧。
and there you go.
HTML 现在以粗体标记。
HTML is now marked in bold.
伟大的。
Great.
再说一次，
So again,
我希望你能自己做到这一点
I hope that you manage to do this on your own
因为这对您的学习过程非常重要。
as this is really important for your learning process.